No living creature was hurt during
the production of this show.
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
They are coming, Togay.
Where is Algu?
The truth is like a sharp dagger.
The dagger has one trace while a
word has a thousand traces.
Forgive me, Togay.
Is the enemy smarter than you?
Huh?
Tell me.
I can't trust you...
if I believe in this.
The Alps searched him.
We thought he can't hide anything.
He might have hidden it somewhere
that even the devil can't think of.
Neither Mongols nor Rums...
can't bring anything to my tent.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, my Bey.
My Alps.
You are smarter, braver...
and believer...
than Mongol and Rum soldiers.
- Don't betray my trust.
- Yes, my Bey.
Yes, my Bey.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, my Bey.
If we gave him the golds...
he wouldn't commit the killing.
He thought of that.
He will attack us after what happened.
Our enemies will grow stronger too
when we grow stronger.
After the victories we gain...
these lands will be
attacked by more Mongols and Rums.
We won't ever stop.
Never.
Genghis Khan, by Tengri's (God) power...
if I don't keep my promise, may the
curse of dark spirits be upon me!
You will die Osman!
You will die!
What is your command, Osman Bey?
Take measures around
the tent and in Söğüt, brother.
Send news to Umur Bey and Turkmen Beys.
They should take measures too.
We don't know where
Togay will attack from.
We should be careful.
From now on...
we are at a point of no return.
Don't think that I forgave you just
because I didn't send you to Engürü.
You included Osman Bey in this situation
by going to Kayı Tent without telling me.
Tell me.
Why did you do that?
Why did you see Osman Bey?
What was your intention?
I can't recognize you anymore.
Why did you change your
attitude towards Osman Bey?
I thought I owe him.
I didn't want
to leave without saying goodbye.
Is that all?
Is that all you will say?
Isn't it enough?
Don't...
disrespect me.
Don't disrespect your father's orders.
You don't owe anything to
anyone as long as I am here.
I don't think I owe you, father.
As I can't pay away.
We are Osman Bey's hawks.
We will cut the world
off if he commands us to!
We will!
We will always fight...
until we become a state.
We will!
Osman Bey is my Bey, Bamsı Bey is
my father. You are my brothers.
I will live for our claim until I die!
I promise.
Alps.
Why do you swear?
I am here too.
Konya / Seljuqs Palace
Osman.
Osman beat my messenger
and threw him out.
Now, I am asking you.
Do you know what does it mean?
I know.
Osman is rebelling and Togay
will devastate Kayı Tent
Do I need to remind you who made you
sit the throne you engaged?
Osman Bey obviously made a huge mistake.
While I am surrounded by enemies...
I can't take another rebel.
What I should do is to
punish Osman Bey myself.
How will you do that, Sultan mesut?
Will you send the Seljuqs army?
An army for a Bey is a lot.
It is costly.
I am sure you won't like
spending Geyhatu's charge.
Then...
I will summon Osman here.
Don't you think he understands
your real intention?
No if I summon him in a good way.
What are you thinking?
I will invite Osman Bey
offering good gifts.
Then?
It's my job to punish him as a Sultan.
Dinner is ready.
You will be served with pheasant.
Cooked with bay leaf and
zested with ripe plum, as you like.
We may talk about what will happen
to Osman while we are walking.
I have some news from my spy in Kayı Tent.
Osman threw the messenger out of the tent.
And Togay vented
his anger on the messenger.
Osman.
Am I surprised? No, not at all.
Nikola, we had an agreement with Nikola.
He said he would take it from Osman.
- And I would give him gold.
- So?
He would attack my
castle if I didn't give him gold.
- I can't trust Togay anymore.
- However...
You can trust me.
Togay won't attack you.
Because we will attack Togay.
How? Togay is powerful.
You know that, Nikola.
Togay is only angry with Osman.
They will fight each other.
Then we will...
watch them.
Then we will attack...
the survivor.
May the spirits let...
the dark vow...
be broken.
The soldiers are ready.
We are ready to fight, Togay.
On behalf of the
dark forests, dark spirits...
and the dark vows...
May the breath of the death be with us...
May my dark vow will be irrigated...
with Osman's blood.
Blood, blood, blood!
He will die...
tonight!
Kayı Tent will be devastated!
I want Osman alive.
It is my...
dark vow. (oath)
Our attack will wait.
Osman will wait for...
virgins to be sacrificed to die.
Why don't we devastate Kayı Tent?
Geyhatu's man...
made an agreement...
with Sultan.
Osman will be punished by him.
You took a dark vow.
My blood will silence the spirits' anger.
Go now.
Bring your soldiers and the Lords' golds.
Burn all of the villages if necessary.
What will happen to Yarhisar Lord?
I will take care of him.
You should go.
- Salam Alaikum, my Sheikh.
- Alaikum Salam, Osman Bey.
- May it be easy.
- Thank you.
- It will be ready soon, Osman Bey.
- Keep working, my Sheikh.
The dead water becomes blurred.
The devil haunts the one who doesn't work.
Effort makes the heart clean.
The ones who work always remember Allah.
Everything reminds them of...
doomsday, Osman Bey.
We need effort and work, Osman Bey.
Being Ahi means effort and work.
Your agreement with the Mongols is done.
They tried to harm you
when they couldn't take the golds.
Our Allah keeps our lives.
No one can harm us
without Allah's permission.
Yes, Osman Bey.
The heathens need effort.
Our effort for work
increases, our power increases.
Our Alps are
waiting for their duties, my Sheikh
- Salam Alaikum, my Sheikh.
- Alaikum Salam.
My Bey.
Aslan Bey, the emir of Sultan Mesut...
is coming to our tent...
from Konya.
Everyone heard of the
messenger, obviously.
Göktuğ...
as Emir is coming here, prepare
some good food.
Your command, my Bey.
What do you think, my Sheikh?
Why does Sultan send...
his Emir?
I wonder why. Is it because
of the messenger? (ambassador)
Maybe, Osman Bey.
However, Sultan Mesut is tied to the
Mongols.
His hands are tied.
Yes.
That's why those
heathens, Mongols, come here and...
ask for our golds.
We have hope, Osman Bey.
We have effort and hope.
You are right, my Sheikh.
I will go to the tent if you excuse me.
I will talk to the Beys.
Let's hear what Emir has to say.
If you excuse me.
Ertuğrul Ghazi's son Osman Bey!
The victory you've won against Rums...
have impressed our sultan.
He wanted to honor the ghazi
who made the victory possible.
He presents you this robe of honor.
My grandfather Süleyman Shah...
and my father Ertuğrul Ghazi
were given lands here...
by the Seljuks. They helped us
make here our home.
We are grateful. We see its future
as ours...
as do we see its cause
as ours.
And we put our effort to
deserve...
the robe of honor that our
sultan sent.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
May your sword be sharp.
Amin.
With the name of Allah.
Enjoy your meal.
Osman Bey, I see that the traditions
of our ancestors are alive with you.
If we forget our traditions,
we'll lose our light.
If we lose our light, we'll never
see forward.
Inshallah, our sultan too will see
you with his own eyes.
Osman Bey, our sultan is inviting you
to the Konya Palace.
A blessing from our sultan.
It's impossible to decline this blessing.
The threat of Togay that Geyhatu sent
after us...
is known by you.
He sent a killer
to kill me in my tribe...
and he is with him
instead of the taxes he expected.
We expect him to attack from somewhere.
Don't worry, Osman Bey.
Our sultan is informed.
He made an agreement with the Mongols
to not attack you.
It seems that our sultan approves
the answer...
that Osman Bey gave to the
attack he received.
Gündüz Bey, you know how it is.
It isn't about a messenger but
the fact that Osman Bey doesn't pay taxes.
This needs to be resolved at once.
If our sultan wants to act considering
the interests...
of the Kayı tribe...
if he assures that Kayı tribe...
will not be harmed...
Then...
it is a duty to answer to his call.
Osman Bey...
be at ease now.
If your life is under the protection of
our sultan.
Until you safely return to your tribe...
we'll keep our hands on our
swords...
and we'll wait for your news.
It is true what I heard about the Kayı
Tribe. Now I've seen it with my eyes.
With the name of Allah.
Enjoy your meals.
For this flag that my ancestors left...
for this flag that...
many of my ghazis
and martyrs have their blood on...
I struggled a lot. To not let this
flag fall down...
I fought to the death with the
most vicious enemies.
But...
no support or whatsoever...
All on our own, we came to these
days by fighting.
And from now, we'll still
be on be our own.
Osman Bey is given the robe
of honor.
Osman Bey is invited.
My Bey, our sultan giving you
the robe of honor...
sending you an invite is equal
to facing the Mongol.
How can he dare to face
the Mongols?
And haven't you heard the man, my bey?
Emir didn't mention the battles Osman
Bey has done with Togay.
The compliment he is getting is
for the victory against the Rum heathens.
Maybe you are right, Malhun.
But Osman Bey's influence...
on Turkmen tribes is increasing.
I will show them what
jihad means...
what beating the heathens means...
they'll learn.
Now...
it is time to make a move!
Your reputation is spreading.
Your name is heard from Konya, Osman Bey.
-Do you think that dark clouds are gone?
-They will.
For sure, Bala.
Good days are at our door.
Inshallah.
There is something gnawing you, Bala.
Don't you know, Osman?
Don't you know the trouble
that has no cure?
I remember it every time you
talk about good days.
If we won't have children,
how will we have good days?
This is the only question I don't
know the answer of.
This is the only enemy that
I'm helpless against.
It's not that hard, Osman.
You'll have a worthy wife.
You will have an heir.
-But I--
-I don't call the trouble my enemy.
Every bey has an enemy.
But the trouble in your heart...
that leaves me helpless.
The fact that you will be sad
ties my hands.
You have such a beautiful heart.
May Allah give you everything you want.
Bala...
Amin. Amin.
Inshallah, Bala.
Amin.
Brother. The tribe is
under your protection.
Even if he is an emir of the Seljuks,
you can't trust the Mongols.
Don't worry, Osman Bey.
We protect the tribe.
-Godspeed.
-Thank you, brother.
Osman Bey... Osman Bey...
Konya is as much as in chaos as here.
Be careful.
May Allah accompany you.
Thank you, Bamsı Bey.
Thank you.
You should go now.
Take care of yourself.
Osman Bey will notice your absence.
Go now.
Boran!
Go.
You are pretty when you are angry, Gonca.
Osman dismissed your messenger, and
destroyed your dignity, I've heard.
It would be a lie if I said I'm sorry.
I warned you Togay.
But you didn't listen to me.
I'll leave none alive when the time comes,
Nicola.
You are all alone now.
Now that you think there's a right time,
I'll just sit in my corner and watch you.
Seljuqi Sultan will punish Osman, not me.
Since when Seljuqi Sultan has been
dealing with Beys?
I am not intrested in your politics.
Either Yarhisar Lord pays his taxes...
or I'll handle it with my soldiers.
Yarhisar Castle's walls will be
his graveyard.
You are taking it all out on us...
because you couldn't storm at Osman?
I am not taking my anger out of anyone,
Nicola.
We had an agreement, if you remember.
Yason can't pay his taxes unless...
Osman pays you.
There's no agreement.
I'll collect tax from Yarhisar Lord
myself.
You are very impatient.
I'll talk to Yason.
This is Yason's last chance, Nicola.
Your dignity is going to be vanished
when I...
stick his pathetic head in my spear
in front of Yarhisar Castle's walls.
Do I make myself clear, Nicola?
Open the door!
Perfectly clear, Togay.
Perfectly clear.
Are we going to do whatever
those vandals want?
I remind you, Nicola. They retreated
even though we had an agreement.
He wants to go to Yason.
His feet will not be
carrying his stupid head.
Togay underestimated me.
He'll pay dearly.
He didn't attack Osman. Alright,
we'll hit Togay then.
- Our soldiers are not enough.
- Helen!
We'll collaborate with Togay's enemy.
- Who?
- Who.
Umur Bey.
My enemy's enemy is my friend.
Are you still here, Helen?
Inform Umur Bey that I want to host
him in my castle.
With a great pleasure, sir.
Dimos, where are you hurrily off to?
Are you sure Dimos is in service of
Yarhisar Lord?
He was always in his service.
He even did his dirty jobs.
I'm sure.
I shudder to think that he can betray
Osman Bey, Cerkutay.
Let's see how much
you can endure.
Let's see what you're going to tell us
when we rip your skin out of your bones.
He feels like in his barn when he
is in battlefield.
He helps his rider fight in war.
He is a brave and stubborn horse.
He is elegant with his beauty.
He is fast and tough.
He has more than every characteristics
one horse should have.
Can he breed?
The filly he mated will give birth
next month.
Nicola, let me gift him to you.
Osman dismissed Togay's messenger who
he sent to collect tax.
Sultan Mesut promoted Osman instead of
call Osman to account.
I don't know what kind of politics is this
in Konya but I'm sick of it, Umur Bey.
Osman's star is shining in Sultan's eyes.
What are you trying to tell me, Nicola?
- Togay.
- What happened to that dog?
That vandal, that arrogant Shaman...
is your and my common enemy.
He will finish what he has left unfinished
as he follows you.
Do not forget: He troubled us all
because he wanted to call you to account
for what you've done in Anatolia.
I pray every day to face that dog.
Your prayer is accepted.
Osman the shining star on one hand, Togay
who is shackled by Sultan on the other hand.
Togay's death will not only glorify you,
Umur Bey.
It will also be enough to kill
Osman's star.
But if I have a decent Bey who has...
decent horses, decent riders and alps...
on my side, then we can end Togay.
However, I am not sure if you
partner up with me...
without informing Osman Bey.
I and Osman Bey are not responsible
for each other.
Tell me how.
I'll give you a secret, Umur Bey.
You know I trust you.
I am listening to you, tell me.
We are sick of Togay troubling
my soldiers.
A decent Bey and his alps on my side
would end Togay.
I understand your idea.
Now that you think I'm decent...
I want to hear your plan.
Here is my plan...
Togay will go to Yarhisar Lord to
collect his taxes.
In the moment he least expected, your
valiant alps and my soldiers entrap him.
Then my prayers will be accepted.
Your dignity will improve in
Turkish tents.
Osman can rest in your shade,
Umur Bey.
When will Togay set off to
Lord Yason?
Let's talk about these in dinner, Umur Bey.
Don't resist!
You had Melih killed, huh?
Yes, yes.
You have to give me proper information...
or I'll drown you in the water.
- This is all I know.
- This is all you know.
Is this all you know?
I can't hear you?
Can't hear you?
Nicola will partner up with Lord Yason
and attack Togay.
If you're lying, what am I going
to do with you?
Swear to god, swear to god.
I am telling the truth.
We'll see.
We'll see if you are right.
Alps!
Take him to caged tent.
Go.
Go!
Come son, come.
Did you hear him, Bamsı Bey?
Old friends became enemies.
That's okay, let them
fight each other.
It's good for us.
But son, Nicola must has someting
else in his mind. He can't defeat Togay.
I won't kill him Bamsı Bey.
We'll take care of him when Osman Bey comes back.
We are going through an era in which we
don't know who is friend and who's enemy.
What are we going to do with the
refugees Bamsı Bey?
How will we understand who is
traitor and who is not?
Son, every one of them is our guest.
We won't discriminate.
We need to host them, Also, we
need to keep an eye on them.
One trouble comes over another.
Yes son. Big guys have big problems.
Osman Bey's troubles will get bigger
as he grows.
But son, he'll get over every difficulty...
as he has a brother like you.
Eyvallah, Bamsı Bey, Eyvallah (thank you).
I'll take you to Sultan's presence
in the morning.
Now you should rest.
You had a long trip.
Tell me.
What is Sultan like?
Sultan Mesut was a hope for the people who
had no peace for a long time.
What about now? Is he depended to
Mongol governors?
Osman Bey, as you know, since Mongols
arrived, taxes are heavier.
There is famine.
Our Sultan is trying to sustain the state.
He hopes to unite when Mongols
leave someday.
He is dealing with self ordained Beys
like you.
You shall rest now.
We had a long trip Boran. Bey told us to
get a proper rest.
Close your eyes.
I can't sleep brother.
What are you thinking?
I am thinking about the great Seljuqs,
the glorious palace in which...
Sultan Aladdin had lived.
- Now...
- What now?
I see the palace is under the shadow of...
randy Mongol soldiers.
I am afraid that this Palace swallow
my Osman Bey.
I am uneasy.
This comfy bed is like a bog for me.
Okay then brother.
What are we waiting for?
Let's go.
Our Bey is staying in this room.
Then we wait our Bey here.
Are you at ease now, my Boran?
I am, brother.
We'll hit that dog Togay who wanted to
attack us when we just landed in here...
who shed our blood...
in the moment he least expected.
My Bey, is it right to do this
without telling Osman Bey?
We partner up with Nicola to attack
Togay. It's politics, Malhun.
Besides, I won't have permission from
Osman Bey to attack my enemy!
Alps!
I see you didn't sleep in the night.
We decided to sacrifice our sleep
with Goktug, my Bey.
You did the same, as I can see, my Bey.
We were afraid that they'd attempt
something, my Bey.
There are so many Mongols in the Palace.
Our Sultan is waiting for you Osman Bey.
Okay.
Alps, bring the present.
Don't bother.
We shall go.
Osman Bey wants to come in
our Sultan's presence.
Deliver your swords first.
You have to lean while going in, my Bey.
Do not talk without Sultan's permission.
Do not look in the eye of Sultan
while talking.
This is tradition.
Our Sultan is the other side of the doors.
Doors!
Kayı Bey Ertugrul Ghazi's son Osman Bey.
You brought presents, Osman Bey.
I wanted to return my Sultan's favor.
In these chests, there are other Turk
Beys' presents too.
What is this?
This is Sultan Aladdin's present for my father.
He sit in this throne long before you did.
Why are you giving this precious gift
of Sultan to me?
The value of this present is not about
its valued rocks on it.
it's about how great our state is, which
was revived by Sultan Aladdin.
I wanted you to keep it.
So that you always remember...
how great your state is.
Judge of Governor.
So, Gokboru Osman is you...
who is self ordained, who Togay
was talking about.
There's something wrong Boran,
be ready.
He entered the room without permission.
Brother, let this life be haram(banned)
to us...
if we can't kill at least ten men
for each of us.
Agreed, brother.
Judge of governor, you honored us.
I have things to ask Osman Bey.
You promised to be Togay's city,
but you killed my messenger.
Do you know what this costs
to you, Osman Bey?
I want to know what this is about,
Osman Bey!
The sneaky one they sent as messenger
tried to kill me...
with his dagger.
You are lying!
My Sultan, I think Togay lost
his temper and killed him...
after I sent him back to Togay.
Go ask Togay.
I protected my tribe's honor,
and my own life as a Bey.
I forgived his life while I should have
killed him.
The rest does not concern me.
Did my messenger tried to kill you when he
heard you wasn't giving taxes?
My Sultan, as you know,
we don't kill the messenger.
What about taxes?
Do you want me to come to your tent,
shed your blood and collect taxes Osman Bey?
If you be a rebel and don't pay your tax..
It'll be my mission to
take your wealth and your life, Osman Bey.
Do not do something wrong.
Do not make me kill a noble Bey
of my own race.
I told Osman Bey what I had to tell. You
have anything to say, judge of governor?
Maybe it's the best thing to end
Gokboru here...
before he bites my soldiers.
Crushing Gokboru's head
while he is little...
or not?
Geyhatu's request is clear...
Judge of governor.
First taxes, then regulation.
You have to obey for both.
You saved your life with gold, Osman Bey.
Thank to your Sultan.
Pay your tax to Togay immediately.
Judge!
I will not pay it to Togay.
I'll pay it to my Sultan.
I am responsible for this, judge.
I am not intrested in the source of money.
I want it to be paid on time.
But, if I don't have it on time...
then, I'll hold you responsible...
for everything, Sultan Mesut.
Do you have anything else to say,
Osman Bey?
Sultan Aladdin's dagger...
is in the wrong person.
Excuse me, my Sultan.
- Osman Bey...
- Everything has been said, my Sultan.
Heart speaks when your tongue can't.
From now on...
the rest is up to Allah.
- My Bey...
- Let's go back to tent at once.
Can I come in my bey?
Come!
My Bey.
From Nicola.
What does Nicola say, my Bey?
He says Togay will collect tax
from Yarhisar.
Nicola knows his path.
- He wants to attack him on his way.
- What are we going to do my Bey?
What do you mean what are we
going to do? Inform my alps!
We'll unsheath our swords for revenge!
As you order, my bey.
My bey, are you sure?
What if it's Nikola's plan?
Don't worry. We'll take our measures
accordingly.
I knew that they would
do mischief, my bey.
Beware!
Alps.
Sheathe your swords.
What coincidence is this, Osman Bey?
I thought you left the palace.
If it's the last time we
encounter each other...
I want to talk to you personally.
Come with me.
Alps. Keep your eyes on the soldiers.
- Alright, my bey.
What is this sultan doing?
Patience, brother.
Have patience.
Patience until Osman bey
establishes the state.
I know how you defeated Lord Nikola.
You proved that you are a great bey
just like your father.
Know that I want you to be loyal to
my ancestor Aladdin's memory.
I'm doing everything I can to protect
you and your tribe from the Mongols.
Don't put yourself or me
in a difficult spot.
My respect for you and my loyalty
to the past...
has a limit.
And that limit is the tax of the Mongols.
I know.
Karamanoğulları is preparing
to move against me.
The claim my throne.
The topliners of the city are in
a difficult situation.
My brother will come to Konya
from Kayseri with his forces.
These are all measures I'm taking
to...
protect the state of my
ancestor Aladdin, Osman Bey.
Will the incoming army be enough
to stop the Karamanoğulları?
What if it's not enough?
I'll have to ask for Geyhatu's help.
If Geyhatu comes, will he not
pillage the whole city?
I neither have the strenght
to face the Mongols...
nor the power.
My only intention is to keep
my state alive.
Otherwise, neither my state
nor your tribe will survive.
Geyhatu's governor and Togay are
looking for an opportunity to kill you.
I stopped both the governor and
Togay for now.
At what cost?
At the cost of my throne and blood.
Don't forget that.
Seemingly obeying the Mongols is
a condition for our state and your tribe.
For this reason, staying patient for a
little longer benefits everyone.
Do you say that we should gain power
enough to stand against the Mongols?
There is no other way, Osman Bey.
I know that I'm right.
I'll even send an army to support you.
Of course, if you act wisely.
Otherwise, we'll both lose.
If the pillar of the state falls,
we'll all be crushed.
I hope you understand.
My eyes will be on Togay...
and ears on you, my sultan.
But know that, sheathing my sword...
will not happen by my choice.
Then, godspeed, Osman Bey.
I'm at ease.
So should you.
Thank you.
Did the lords pay their taxes?
They did, Togay.
We returned with gold.
We'll go to Yasu.
Nikola is very angry about that
I betrayed him.
He'll seek vengeance.
We'll be ready as the doomsday
will come.
Yasu won't dare that.
If he listens to Nikola
and set a trap...
my grave will be his last
shelter.
What about Osman?
What about your dark oath?
The spirits have other
plans with the Gökbörü.
Our hands are tied. We'll wait
until they are freed.
The sultan wants us to keep
the act against the Mongols.
The Kayıs will pay their taxes
to the Seljuks.
Not to the Mongols.
And he'll give soldiers?
The Mongols will think that we
are their vassals.
And we'll have the sultan's support...
and gain strenght.
If you get soldiers after the robe of honor,
you'll gain a lot of reputation, my bey.
The Turkmen beys will be united
behind us.
To stand stronger against
the armies of Ilkhaganete...
this is what needs to be done.
Now, I will send a
messenger to Togay.
I will tell him that we obey him.
That messenger will let him know that
we pay the taxes to the Seljuks.
But Osman Bey, we know your
intentions...
but being seen like
a vassal to the Mongols...
will sow discontent
among other beys.
I know, Osman Bey.
I know. I'll talk to every bey.
I'll tell them all about it
and what we think.
I'll go to Umur Bey who fought with
the Mongols a lot personally.
-So, brother?
-We caught a traitor named Dimos here.
We took an informant information
from him.
The lord of Yarhisar and Nikola are
planning to attack Togay.
Inshallah they won't leave the
battlefield until the last man.
Inshallah, Bamsı Bey.
Inshallah.
I will not attack Togay for the
deal I've made with the sultan.
But if Nikola does...
this will benefit me.
Let them kill each other while
we gain power.
When the time comes,
we'll crush them all.
-Inshallah.
-Thank Allah.
Togay will take this way to
collect the taxes.
And I will wait for him here
with my army.
And I will cut off his escape
from here.
Umur Bey's alps will position here.
Togay will be between three
forces.
Not three, four.
Your soldiers will attack from behind.
Let's see if Togay's most trusted
spirits will save him from here.
My bey, the poor people that
took refuge in our tribe...
wanted to thank you for letting
them do their worship.
They've been waiting for you
for a long time, my bey.
Did you think about the kids?
As you always order, my bey.
Here, my bey.
Thank you.
Come on.
Welcome, Osman Bey.
Thank you.
Here it is.
Take some.
Here.
Mashallah.
Not at all. Not at all.
Not at all.
May Jesus Christ help you, Osman Bey.
You opened your arms for us.
You gave us food.
You gave us houses and a place
to pray.
You opened your arms for us.
You gave us food.
You gave us houses and a place
to pray.
-May Mother Mary watch over you.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-Do you lack anything?
-We have everything, Osman Bey.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
Thanks to you, Osman Bey.
May God watch over you, Osman Bey.
We have everything, Osman Bey.
-Does the church need anything?
-It has everything, Osman Bey.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
God bless you, Osman Bey.
If you need anything, come to me.
Come to me. Now, you are our guests.
If you feel comfortable,
so will we.
Osman Bey, you call us guests but we
don't want to hear that word.
Why is that? Tell me.
We don't want to be guests but
persistent.
We want to live under your flag, secured
by your justice.
Mashallah.
If so, you will not be called guests.
Now, you are at home.
Live as you want and
pray as you want.
God bless you, Osman Bey.
Thank you. You too.
You too.
What's wrong, Cerkutay?
Had something happened at the tribe?
Not at the tribe. Something is
happening in here! In here!
The cure is here, Cerkutay. But our
sheik is resting.
Tell him ''You said come here...
and he came.''
He will understand.
Come, Cerkutay.
Come. Let's not keep our sheik waiting.
Two of the refugees were sick.
Now they are better.
The herds are cadging now.
Spring is coming, Osman.
The people helped in foodbanks
are decreasing too.
-Why, Bala?
-We are having less poor people, Osman Bey.
Thank Allah.
There was Hatice Hatun...
she read Yasin surah to the women
at Bayhoca's funeral.
Her daughter, Emine had a baby.
It was so cute--
Why are you silent, my nightingale?
I can listen to you all day.
I wish you could listen to the
sound of your children here.
You still haven't done what
Ertuğrul Ghazi wanted, Osman Bey.
-When you--
-It will happen as Allah wants.
It will happen when Allah wants.
O' valiant with a Muslim's heart!
What are you waiting for to convert?
I'm a daemon.
I killed many.
I killed women and children too.
How can I be a Muslim?
I can't look at Muhammad.
I'm afraid of his Allah.
How can one be afraid of his loved one?
Just swear off.
One who admits his tyranny can enter.
Our door is open for them.
Can you read me something from that book?
I swear to mid-morning...
I swear to midnight that...
your Allah has not abandoned you.
Neither is he offended.
For sure, the afterlife is better
for you than this life.
For sure, your Allah will give you...
and you will be pleased.
Did he not find you an orphan and
provided you shelter?
Did he not find you lost and
gave you a path?
Did he not find you in need
and make you rich?
Then, don't oppress the orphans.
Don't scold the ones who ask.
And about the felicity of your Allah...
talk about it.
Is my Allah telling this to me?
Your Allah is telling it to his
most beloved subject...
Muhammad Mustafa.
It's like he is telling me
as well.
Understanding Qur-an is...
understanding that we are object
of every subject in Qur-an, Cerkutay.
And about the shada...
shada...
is the tears in your eyes.
Witnessing that Allah is one and only...
Hz.Muhammad is his subject and messenger..
can only be done by feeling every verse
of Qur-an like this.
I witness.
This religion is my religion.
-Then repeat after me.
-I'm ready.
I bear witness that there is no
god but Allah...
and I bear witness that Muhammad
is the servant and Messenger of Allah.
and I bear witness that Muhammad...
-is the servant and...
...Messenger of Allah.
With the name of Allah.
You are among the Muslims.
War is cheating, daughter.
Surprising the enemy assures victory.
Togay doesn't expect us to attack.
So, he will be off guard.
-There is someone else who doesn't expect.
-Is that so? Who is that?
May I enter, Umur Bey?
Come in, Osman Bey!
-We would prepare if you had told us.
-Thank you, Umur Bey. Thank you.
We had urgent jobs to take care of.
I would like to eat with you
if we find time.
Inshallah.
Come, Osman Bey.
You know why I went to Konya,
Umur Bey.
I know, Osman Bey.
I wonder what you talked to our sultan.
That's why I'm here.
We agreed...
with the sultan,
on the matter of...
staying as vassals of the
Mongol for a little longer.
I wanted you to hear it from me, Umur Bey.
Hearing it directly from you...
doesn't change our response.
We migrated here, burying our
martyrs on the way.
Not only our alps but our women and
children too!
No one can ask me to be a vassal
of the Mongol...
even if it's for the politics.
Umur Bey, we've also had that.
We came here while fighting
with the Mongols.
Don't let our bow mistaken you.
The bow is pulled now.
The arrow will find its target.
You pull your bow and release
your arrow.
And I will swing my blade.
Everyone will do as they know.
Umur Bey.
The sultan is talking about giving
soldiers.
Think about it well.
Understand it.
I'm not talking about a bunch of alps
but an army.
I'm talking about facing the Ilkhaganete
army...
not chasing Togay around.
I'm not talking about saving
our tribes...
but breaking the chains of
all Turkish tribes.
Osman Bey, Sultan Mesut can't act unless
the Mongols order. You trust him too much.
I'm determined on shaping the
fate of my tribe.
Umur Bey! Being stubborn helps no one.
If we don't act wise, all the
Turkmen tribes are in danger.
Even Karamanoğulları and
Germiyanoğulları...
are subjects of the Mongols.
Even the all Turkmen tribes...
can't stand against
Ilkhaganate armies.
I have a blood feud with Togay.
I don't need anyone's help
to end that feud.
Umur Bey!
Why is the haste, Umur Bey?
Why is the haste?
Nikola and the lord of Yarhisar will
attack Togay.
Let them attack. Let them
tore each other apart.
And then, we will take action.
You can act as you want.
I will attack Togay.
-I will never allow such an attack.
-Osman Bey! Father!
Your goal is the same.
But you have different methods.
Don't say things that are impossible
to take back.
I have spoken.
I don't ask for permission to attack
my archenemy.
Umur Bey...
If you act your own and
fail my plan...
then, I'm not responsible
of what happens.
Know that.
Do you see?
How he threatens us...
My bey, don't!
We need unity.
You should've told that to
Osman Bey, not me.
I will, then!
Osman Bey!
Wait!
I have things to say.
Osman Bey, Umur Bey's intentions are
good. Be understanding.
It isn't as hard as it seems to
find a middle ground.
Malhun Hatun, I understand
your efforts, I admire it.
But I have spoken.
It is Umur Bey who
disrespects my word.
Now, it's his responsibility.
Alps! Come on!
Göktuğ!
Keep your eyes on Umur Bey's tribe.
I want to know all his moves.
As you order, my bey.
-Allah is ever living!
-Allah is true!
Kumral Abdal! If you hold it like
that, you can't use all your power!
Come on, Kumral Abdal!
We have many swords to make!
Who taught this woman to use
it like this.
-Salam Alaikum.
-Alaikum Salam.
-Where did that come from?
-Good day.
Thank you.
-It's about a good event.
-Who is getting married?
A young man who became a Muslim
is handing out food.
Who is that young man?
He spent the last night at
Sheik Edebali's lodge.
He is handing food out today.
Who do you think he is?
Cerkutay.
He has no money.
-How did he afford it?
-He sold his armor.
-You sold your armor, huh?
-Yeah.
Now it's on us.
The women of the Kayı will prepare you
alp clothes and armor.
-It will be ready before Osman Bey comes.
-Alp clothes?
And Master Davud will afford it.
Kumral Abdal said that he is hopeful
about that mad lad.
Don't underestimate Kumral Abdal's
wisedom, Osman Bey.
Not at all, my sheik.
Not at all!
Kumral Abdal enlightened the night
that was in Cerkutay's heart like a crescent.
That crescent turned into a half moon
with Bamsı Bey.
And it turned into a full moon with
your light.
Not at all.
He told me that the first light was the
moment he saw you performing salaat.
I will perform ablution with the water
and perform salaat.
-Then, we'll be on our way.
-Is it time? Our enemies are waiting.
Nothing can stop us from
praying to our Allah.
Look at him. We can cut his throat
if we want it.
He isn't afraid.
Dying for their faith is most
wanted by the Muslims.
He has faith as strong
as a rock.
If we had his faith, we would make
the world our slave.
Is that so, my sheik?
Is that so?
Mashallah.
My sheik.
The sultan wants us to act as vassals
to the Mongol.
But Umur Bey seems like he will
ruin my plans.
This cause sees no relations.
If he attacks Togay...
if he destroys the plan I've
made with the sultan...
then my answer will be harsh.
If this disagreement turns
into animosity...
it won't be good for the Turkmens,
Osman Bey.
It won't, my sheik.
It won't. But it seems that way.
Inshallah, Allah will unite
the paths of...
those who seek the
same destination.
Inshallah, my sheik.
Inshallah.
You can leave, Osman Bey.
Thank you.
Now it's on us, dear friends.
We have to put these two beys
on the same path again.
Or the future of the Turkmens
is doomed.
May I enter, my bey?
Come, Cerkutay!
Come closer.
May Allah bless it. May you become
a renowned ghazi...
who serves to the Kayı,
to Islam.
The salaat. The salaat is the
foundation of the religion.
It's how the subject reaches
to Allah.
For this reason, you can remember that
you are a subject, five times a day.
You can remember who is giving
the food you eat.
Here.
I've become a Muslim. I'll do
everything I need to, my bey.
If my Allah forgives even
a man like me...
I will do everything he wants
me to do.
Mashallah.
This is our book.
Our path, our light,
the crown of our heads.
We are responsible for every
verse it has.
And we'll serve it until the
end of times.
Mashallah.
-May I enter, my bey?
-Come in, Göktuğ.
My bey, Umur Bey and his
alps are preparing.
It seems that they'll move
on the dawn.
He will attack, huh?
-Prepare all the alps, brother.
-Is your decision final, Osman Bey?
-My decision is final, Bamsı Bey.
-If Umur Bey doesn't step back...
will you spill Turkmen blood?
-Umur Bey left the tribe with his alps.
-Good.
Let's greet Togay nicely.
Umur Bey!
My decision is final!
I won't let you destroy the future
of the Muslims for your personal grudge!
Return at once!
This is the end of words, Osman Bey!
Get away from the jihadists!
Osman Bey! My bey!
What are you doing?
Malhun! Get back.
I won't say it again.
I'm saying it for the last time, Osman
Bey. Open the way for the jihadists.
Umur Bey!
Don't force me to do things that
I don't want to!
Stop!
-My sheik.
-Osman Bey, stop.
If you want it, I'll do anything.
Umur Bey, what are you doing?
Return at once.
My sheik, I trust your justice.
But you say stop to Osman Bey...
and you say return to us.
If we were content with returning,
this wouldn't happen.
You disrespected Osman Bey's words.
-Will you respect mine too?
-Aren't we supposed to jihad, my sheik?
We are.
But starting disunion is haram.
It will happen as my sheik says.
We came here for jihad.
Allah knows that...
no one else but Edebali could
convince me to return.
Come on.
We are returning to the tribe.
Osman Bey. I have things to
tell you.
Go on, my sheik.
This animosity must end for
the sake of the Turkmens.
You are right, my sheik.
There is only one way.
You will do as Ertuğrul Ghazi said.
You will marry with Umur Bey's
daughter...
Malhun Hatun.